STEPHANIE J. NELMS

1125 KENSINGTON DR. DESOTO , TX 75115 Cell 682-215-9561 MSG 469-297-0315 STEPHANIENELMS1@GMAIL.COM

1. CAREER SUMMARY

To utilize my vast experience in assisting with patient care procedures, medical clerical duties, and other duties as assigned. Experienced medical professional with 8 years as a medical assistant. Dedicated to providing the standard level of care to patients while providing support to team members.

1.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Baylor University Medical University

2013-2015

- Assisting the Nursing Staff with the Care of the Sick & Elderly
- Assisting some Resident's with Therapy transitiong to home
- Assisting the Resident's with everyday living situations

Diabetic Fingersticks

Assisting with feedings of patients as needed

Answering incoming phone calls on the unit

Making courtesy calls to discharged patients following up

- Reporting any changes in the conditions of the residents to nursing staff & doctors
- Charting fluid intake & outputs
- Vital Signs

Senior Care Centers

2010 - 2011

CNA

- Assisting the Nurses / Nursing Staff with the Care of the Sick & Elderly .
- Assisting the Resident's with everyday living situations
- Helping the Physical Therapy
- Providing the best possible care for the welfare of the resident's
- Providing Companionship, just basic attention for the resident's
- Maintained homelike environment for the resident's
- Obtained specimens, weights and vital signs of patients
- Maintaining Patient's Right and Privacy
- Assist in movements of patients through wheelchairs and walking
- Training new aides on different care procedure's
- Provide Restorative Care
- Provide bed wash, dress and undress and feed patients
- Care of dementia or cognitively suffered patients
- Keeping daily record of fluid intake by patients
- Respect patient's right of independence and confidentiality

Dallas Center for Rehabilitation

2009-2010

- CNA
- Assisting with Activities of Daily Living
- Assisting the Nursing Staff as well as the Doctor's with Minor Procedure's
- Light House Keeping / Laundry
- Serving Meal's during Meal Time

- Helping resident's to get prepared to for bed at night
- Assisted resident's with bathing, dressing, hygiene, and grooming in accordance with established care plan.
- Measured and recorded patient's fluid intake and output

Methodist Health System

2008-2009

PCT

- Taking Vital Signs
- Performing Venipuncture's
- Doing Blood Glucose Testing
- Given enemas to patient when needed
- Ensured the safety and well being of the resident's is maintained
- Provided routine care to the patient's
- Obtained specimens, weights, and vital signs of patients
- Remove or releases restraints as scheduled
- Clean up spills on the floor in order to prevent accidents
- Keep notes on patients while on duty
- Note any unusual changes in resident's condition and report to charge nurse
- Verbally communicate nursing care problems and concerns to on coming shift on assigned unit
- Attend and participate in unit meetings

St . Michael's Hospice Hospice Aide / CNA

2006-2007

- Providing TLC to the Terminally III patient's & Family Member's
- Traveling to Patient's home, living care facilities, where the care is needed
- Helping the family in time of need as well as the patient receiving the care
- Provided support in the form of analysis of behavior for children and adults
- Made observations and analysis of adults in their living environments
- Assisting the treatment of the subjects
- Understanding the patient's problems and trying to offer the appropriate solution
- Performed delegated patient care activities in the home
- Monitored and reported significant changes in patient condition
- Communicated appropriate information to members of the team

Manor Care of Dallas

2005-2006

CNA

- Showering, assisting resident's with meal's,
- Some Physical Therapy , Assisting to the Bathroom , basic ADL 's
- Turn and position bed patients according to turning schedules
- Use mechanical lifts during transfers
- Perform range of motion on resident's as ordered
- Note any unusual changes in resident's condition and report to nurse
- Keep linen and utility area clean and in order empty and clean urinals and bedpans
- Perform incontinence checks on resident's every two hours
- Record data for BM's and weight sheet and Nurse Aide flow sheet

EDUCATION

Mesquite High School

1994-1998

3. <u>CERTIFICATIONS</u> BLS

BLS 2008- Present